{
  "1": {
    "question": "The Indian National Congress was founded by:",
    "options": {
      "a": "A.O.Hume",
      "b": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
      "c": "Motilal Nehru",
      "d": "Surendranath Banerjee"
    },
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "On 28 December 1885, the Indian National Congress was founded at Gokuldas Tejpal Sanskrit College in Bombay, with 72 delegates in attendance. Hume assumed office as the General Secretary, and Womesh Chunder Bonnerjee of Calcutta was elected President.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "2": {
    "question": "The author of 'Poverty and Un-British Rule in India is",
    "options": {
      "a": "R. C. Dutt",
      "b": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
      "c": "Lala Lajpat Rai",
      "d": "Surendra Nath Banerjee"
    },
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "In 1867, Dadabhai Naoroji put forward the 'drain of wealth' theory in which he stated that the Britain was completely draining India. He mentioned this theory in his book Poverty and Un-British Rule in India.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "3": {
    "question": "Who among the following was popularly known as the Frontier Gandhi?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Hasrat Mohani",
      "b": "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad",
      "c": "Khan Abdul Ghaffar Khan",
      "d": "Iqbal Khan"
    },
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "Khan Abdul Ghaffar Khan, leader of the Pukhtuns, was given the sobriquet of 'Sarhadi Gandhi' by his followers in reference to his commitment to the freedom struggle and non-violence. Ghaffar Khan was a great admirer of Mahatma Gandhi.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "4": {
    "question": "When did the First World War begin?",
    "options": {
      "a": "28th July 1914",
      "b": "20th July 1913",
      "c": "28th May 1900",
      "d": "28th June 1914"
    },
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "World War I, also known as the First World War, the Great War, and initially in North America as the European War, was a global war originating in Europe that lasted from 28 July 1914 to 11 November 1918.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "5": {
    "question": "In the eighteenth century, which king was regarded as 'the most dangerous rival' in Mysore by the British?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Banda Bahadur",
      "b": "Ahmed Shah Abdali",
      "c": "Shah Alam II",
      "d": "Hyder Ali"
    },
    "answer": "d",
    "more_info": "Hyder Ali was the Sultan and de facto ruler of the Kingdom of Mysore in southern India. Born as Sayyid wal Sharif Hyder Ali Khan, he distinguished himself militarily, eventually drawing the attention of Mysore's rulers.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "6": {
    "question": "Who was the first president of India?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Rajendra Prasad",
      "b": "Ram Nath Kovind",
      "c": "Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan",
      "d": "Mohammad Hidayatullah"
    },
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "Rajendra Prasad (3 December 1884 â€“ 28 February 1963) was an Indian independence activist, lawyer, scholar and subsequently, the first President of India, in office from 1950 to 1962. He was an Indian political leader and lawyer by training.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "7": {
    "question": "The Rowlatt Act was passed in:",
    "options": {
      "a": "1905",
      "b": "1913",
      "c": "1919",
      "d": "1925"
    },
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "The Anarchical and Revolutionary Crimes Act of 1919, popularly known as the Rowlatt Act or Black Act, was passed by the Imperial Legislative Council in Delhi on 10 March 1919, indefinitely extending the emergency measures of preventive indefinite detention, incarceration without trial and judicial review.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "8": {
    "question": "The Gandhi-Irwin Pact was signed on:",
    "options": {
      "a": "July 8, 1931",
      "b": "March 8, 1931",
      "c": "January 8, 1931",
      "d": "June 8, 1931"
    },
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "The Gandhi-Irwin Pact was a political agreement signed by Mahatma Gandhi and Lord Irwin, the then Viceroy of India, on 5 March 1931 before the second Round Table Conference in London.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "9": {
    "question": "Aurobindo Ghose, Barindra Kumar Ghose, B.P. Mitra, Abinash Bhattacharya and Bhupendranath Dutta were associated with the revolutionary organization:",
    "options": {
      "a": "Anushilan Samiti (in Bengal)",
      "b": "Satya Shodhak Samaj",
      "c": "Bengal Society",
      "d": "Lok Pal Party"
    },
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "Aurobindo Ghose, Barindra Kumar Ghose, B.P. Mitra, Abinash Bhattacharya and Bhupendranath Dutta were associated with the revolutionary organization Anushilan Samiti (in Bengal).",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "10": {
    "question": "Who was Henry VIII's last wife?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Catherine of Aragon",
      "b": "Jane Seymour",
      "c": "Catherine Howard",
      "d": "Catherine Parr"
    },
    "answer": "d",
    "more_info": "Catherine Parr, the last of the six wives of King Henry VIII, married him on 12 July 1543, and outlived him by a year and eight months. She was influential in the education of Elizabeth I and Edward VI.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "11": {
    "question": "What colour were the pyramids at Giza originally?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Red",
      "b": "White",
      "c": "Brown",
      "d": "Gray"
    },
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "The pyramids were originally plated in an outer layer of white casing stones made of polished Tura limestone, meant to reflect the sun's rays.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "12": {
    "question": "What was the name of the mythological monster that had nine heads?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Kraken",
      "b": "Scylla",
      "c": "Hydra",
      "d": "Sirens"
    },
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "Hydra, a water-snake-like monster in Greek legend, had nine heads, one of which was immortal.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "13": {
    "question": "Who were the Axis powers in World War II?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Poland, Japan, Germany",
      "b": "Germany, Italy, Japan",
      "c": "Italy, Japan, Britain",
      "d": "Germany, Italy, France"
    },
    "answer": "b",
    "more_info": "The Axis powers in World War II were Germany, Italy, and Japan, opposed by the Allied powers.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "14": {
    "question": "The term 'Cold War' was coined by:",
    "options": {
      "a": "Palmer Perkins",
      "b": "Prof. Lippmann",
      "c": "Bernard Baruch",
      "d": "Roosevelt"
    },
    "answer": "c",
    "more_info": "Bernard Baruch coined the term 'Cold War' to describe the tensions between the United States and the Soviet Union after World War II.",
    "user_response": "None"
  },
  "15": {
    "question": "The East India Association was set up in:",
    "options": {
      "a": "1866",
      "b": "1857",
      "c": "1836",
      "d": "1885"
    },
    "answer": "a",
    "more_info": "The East India Association was founded by Dadabhai Naoroji in 1866 to provide representation for Indians to the British government.",
    "user_response": "None"
  }
}
